No one can stop the reign.
Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes is a science fiction,
adventure, action film directed by Wes Ball.
Several generations following Caesar's reign, apes – now the dominant species – live
harmoniously while humans have been reduced to living in the shadows.
As a new tyrannical ape leader builds his empire, one young ape undertakes a harrowing journey that will cause him to
question all he's known about the past and to make choices that will define a future for apes and humans alike.
Noa, played by Owen Teague.
Nova / Mae, played by Freya Allan.
Proximus Caesar, played by Kevin Durand.
Raka, played by Peter Macon.
Trevathan, played by William H. Macy.
Sylva, played by Eka Darville.
Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes is a 2024 American science fiction
action film directed by Wes Ball and written by Josh Friedman.
It is the fourth installment in the Planet of the Apes reboot film series and the tenth film
overall, serving as a standalone sequel to War for the Planet of the Apes (2017).
The film stars Owen Teague, Freya Allan, Kevin
Durand, Peter Macon, and William H.
It takes place many generations after the events of War and follows Noa (Teague), a young chimpanzee hunter who embarks
on a journey alongside Mae (Allan), a human woman, to determine the future for apes and humans alike.
Development on a new Planet of the Apes film began in April 2019, following Disney's acquisition
of 20th Century Fox, with Ball attached as writer and director that December.
Much of the screenplay was written during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, with
casting commencing in June 2022, following the screenplay's completion.
Teague was cast in the lead role that August, with the film's title and
additional casting announced in the following months.
Principal photography began in October 2022 in Sydney and wrapped in
February 2023, with a budget of $120–160 million.
Kingdom of the Planet of the Apes premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on May 2,
2024, and was released by 20th Century Studios in the United States on May 10.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed over $397 million worldwide.
It received a nomination for Best Visual Effects at the 97th Academy Awards.
A sequel is in development for an expected 2027 release.
The film explores themes of empire, kingdom, gorilla,
dystopia, post-apocalyptic future.
The tone is thought_provoking.